# Gustavo Andrés Salazar Gómez

Last update: February 13, 2021

# Personal data

Name: Gustavo Andrés Salazar Gómez

Date of Birth: April 27th, 1995. (Cali, Colombia)

Nationality: Colombian

Work address: Open International.

Carrera 103 No. 16-20, Ciudad Jardin

Cali, Colombia

Tel: +57(2)331 9999. Ext. 598. https://www.openintl.com/es/

**Position:** Product Specialist - Support Services

Professional Services

Phone: +57 312 814 4758 (Also WhatsApp)
E-mail: gus.salazar2704@gmail.com
Web page: https://gsg213.github.io
Languages: Spanish - Mother language

English - C1 (TOEFL)



#### Profile

I am a disciplined, honest, responsible and proactive person, I have the ease to interact with others, learn quickly and fast understanding of problems. I adapt myself very easily to new environments, perform very well working as a team or individually. I like to learn new things constantly, and I don't fear challenges. I can work under pressure and generate solutions quickly and effectively.

Throughout my academic training and professional course, I have participated in projects concerning instrumentation and electronics, programming, SQL and PL/SQL, software configuration and parameterization, incident diagnosis, classic and intelligent control systems, robotics, artificial neural networks, digital image processing, Machine learning models in supervised learning such as KNN, linear models, linear regression for classification, logistic regression, unsupervised learning such as clustering, dimensionality reduction, unsupervised transformation, feature engineering and Deep learning models. I've worked with platforms such as Azure and AWS to deploy Machine Learning solutions, also using micro-services architectures with tools like Kubernetes, Docker and HAProxy, and I'm still learning much more in an Artificial Intelligence Specialization.

In my current job role I have worked more than a year in support services facing all kind of customers and solving product issues. After that for a year I've been working as first level engineer where I am in charge of technical and functional duties, working side by side and constantly supporting our US client in tasks related to the configuration and parameterization of the product, incidents management and diagnosis, and knowledge transfer. In addition to this, establishing partnership and communication channels with the client to collect and understand their needs, finally propose solutions that are able to meet these requirements for their approval and provide the best experience.

# **Work Experience**

 Feb 2019 - Present date:
 Product Specialist

 Open International.

 Jan 2018 - Dec 2018:
 Robotics teacher

Robotica for kids - Cali.

#### Personal skills:

- Creativity
   Innovation
   Detail orientation
- Adaptability
   Problem Analysis
   Resource management

### **Technical skills:**

- Machine Learning
   Digital Image Processing
   Python(Tensorflow, OpenCV, Scikit-learn)
- Cloud Computing
   Error Diagnosis
   Programming

### **Education**

2020 -	Present date:	Postgraduate diploma in Artificial Intelligence.
		Department of Automatic and Electronic.
		Universidad Autonoma de Occidente – Cali.
2012	2010	

2013 - 2018: BEng Mechatronics Engineering.

Department of Automatic and Electronic.

Universidad Autonoma de Occidente – Cali.

# Research Experience

2016 - 2017: Research area: Design and construction of a scaffold from a biomaterial that serves as support for mesenchymal stem cells (MSC) of bone marrow, for its potential use in the regeneration of the infarcted myocardium of a biomodel. Research Group in Technologies for Manufacture (GITEM) from Universidad Autonoma de Occidente – Cali.

# Distinctions, awards and scholarships

- **2016:** AmeriMex Educational Foundation Scholarship. Amerimex Communications, Roswell, GA, United States of America.
- **2015:** AmeriMex Educational Foundation Scholarship. Amerimex Communications, Roswell, GA, United States of America.
- **2014:** Director's Honor Roll 2014, English proficiency. Language Institute. Universidad Autonoma de Occidente Cali.
- **2013:** Director's Honor Roll 2013, English proficiency. Language Institute. Universidad Autonoma de Occidente Cali.

#### Memberships

**2016** - **2017**: Research Group in Technologies for Manufacture (GITEM) from Universidad Autonoma de Occidente – Cali.

#### **Publications**

2019: Springer Communications in Computer and Information Science book series (CCIS, volume 833), Title: Applications of Computational Intelligence, Chapter: Application of Transfer Learning for Object Recognition Using Convolutional Neural Networks (Extended version). Pages: 14-25 (DOI: 10.1007/978-3-030-03023-0).

**2018:** IEEE 1st Colombian Conference on Applications in Computational Intelligence (ColCACI), Title: Application of Transfer Learning for Object Recognition Using Convolutional Neural Networks, Medellin, Antioquia. (DOI:10.1109/ColCACI.2018.8484856).

# **Personal References**

Carlos Salazar.
Sales Representative - Ria Financial Mobile: +1 678 301 8181
casalazar@riafinancial.com

Nicolas Diaz.

Customer Service Engineer - Siemens Healthineers

Mobile: +57 310 530 2764

nicolasdiazsalazar@gmail.com

Manuela Fernanda Ceron Viveros. Technology Analyst - Open International Mobile: +57 314 712 7879 mafe-cv@hotmail.com

Gustavo Delozers.

Gustavo Andrés Salazar Gómez